Register of the Wisconsin. Governor (1979-1983: Dreyfus): Constituent Correspondence, 1978-1982
Wisconsin Historical Society
Wisconsin. Governor (1979-1983: Dreyfus): Constituent Correspondence, 1978-1982
Wisconsin. Governor (1979-1983: Dreyfus)
1983/056; 1983/057; 1983/064; 1983/074; 1983/179; 1983/180; 1984/026; 1985/172; 1986/070; 1986/197; 1987/155
118.4 c.f.
Wisconsin Historical Society, Library-Archives Division
Incoming letters, copies of replies, inter-office memoranda concerning the inquiry, and face sheets showing office routing and other administrative information. Includes Index to Constituent Correspondence--a computer printout produced by the Dept. of Administration from data entered by the Office's word processing section showing name of correspondent, subject of correspondence, date of receipt, date of reply, and staff member who handled the inquiry.
These records have been assigned Series 3018.
See the Agency History in the catalog.
This collection was received in multiple parts from the donor(s) and is organized into 11 major parts. These materials have not been physically interfiled and researchers might need to consult more than one part to locate similar materials.
Part 1 (1983/056): Original Collection, 1980-1982
Part 2 (1983/057): Additions, 1981
Part 3 (1983/064): Additions, 1979-1982
Part 4 (1983/074): Additions, 1981
Part 5 (1983/179): Additions, 1981-1982
Part 6 (1983/180): Additions, 1980
Part 7 (1984/026): Additions, 1979-1982
Part 8 (1985/172): Additions, 1979, 1982
Part 9 (1986/070): Additions, 1978-1980
Part 10 (1986/197): Additions, 1978
Part 11 (1987/155): Additions, 1979-1980
Administrative/Restriction Information
1983/056, 1983/057, 1983/064, 1983/074, 1983/179, 1983/180, 1984/026, 1985/172, 1986/070, 1986/197, 1987/155
Contents List
- Part 1 (1983/056): Original Collection, 1980-1982, 1983/056; 39.0 c.f. (39 record center cartons)
  Constituent correspondence addressed to Governor Lee Sherman Dreyfus, 1980-1982, arranged by numerical code. Included are incoming letters, copies of replies, inter-office memoranda concerning the inquiry, and face sheets showing office routing and other administrative information.
  - Constituent correspondence - numerical by code
    - 1980
      - 31,000-31,699 (Box 1)
      - 31,700-32,399 (Box 2)
      - 32,400-33,099 (Box 3)
      - 33,100-33,999 (Box 4)
      - 34,000-34,899 (Box 5)
      - 34,900-35,799 (Box 6)
      - 35,800-36,599 (Box 7)
      - 36,600-37,699 (Box 8)
      - 37,700-38,499 (Box 9)
      - 38,500-39,299 (Box 10)
      - 39,300-39,899 (Box 11)
      - 39,900-40,399 (Box 12)
      - 40,400-40,919 (Box 13)
      - 40,920-41,549 (Box 14)
      - 41,550-42,149 (Box 15)
      - 42,150-42,799 (Box 16)
      - 42,800-43,549 (Box 17)
      - 43,550-44,549 (Box 18)
    - 1980-1981
      - 44,550-45,299 (Box 19)
    - 1981
      - 45,300-45,999 (Box 20)
      - 46,000-46,799 (Box 21)
      - 46,800-47,699 (Box 22)
      - 47,700-48,599 (Box 23)
      - 48,600-49,299 (Box 24)
      - 49,300-49,999 (Box 25)
      - 50,000-50,899 (Box 26)
      - 50,900-51,699 (Box 27)
      - 51,700-52,599 (Box 28)
      - 52,600-53,499 (Box 29)
      - 53,500-54,299 (Box 30)
      - 54,300-55,228 (Box 31)
      - 55,229-56,099 (Box 32)
      - 56,100-56,999 (Box 33)
      - 57,000-57,699 (Box 34)
      - 57,700-58,399 (Box 35)
      - 58,400-59,199 (Box 36)
      - 59,200-60,399 (Box 37)
      - 60,400-60,999 (Box 38)
    - 1981-1982
      - 61,000-61,999 (Box 39)
- Part 2 (1983/057): Additions, 1981, 1983/057; 0.4 c.f. (1 archives box)
  Constituent correspondence, 1981, addressed to Governor Dreyfus. The majority of the accession are letters from school children requesting materials such as maps, state symbols, and photos of Dreyfus for reports and personal collections. Also included are requests for state reports and publications to be sent to libraries and professional groups and general letters of support for the governor.
- Part 3 (1983/064): Additions, 1979-1982, 1983/064; 3.0 c.f. (3 record center cartons)
  Indexes to constituent correspondence, 1979-1982. Correspondence is indexed alphabetically and by sender, and for 1979-1981 by subject.
  - Constituent correspondence indices
    - 1980-1982 March
      - Arranged by last name (Box 1)
    - 1979-1981
      - Arranged by subject (Box 2)
      - Arranged by last name (Box 3)
- Part 4 (1983/074): Additions, 1981, 1983/074; 0.2 c.f. (1 archives box)
  Legal and policy correspondence, 1981, sent to the Governor's office or passed on through state representatives. A few of the topics covered include retirement systems, alcohol and drug abuse, and environmental concerns.
- Part 5 (1983/179): Additions, 1981-1982, 1983/179; 1.4 c.f. (1 record center carton and 1 archives box)
  Children's letters and correspondence related to AB 621 legislation which would prohibit abortion in public hospitals, 1981-1982.
  - Abortion correspondence (Box 1, Folder 1-14)
  - Abortion correspondence (continued) (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Children's correspondence (Box 2, Folder 3-6)
- Part 6 (1983/180): Additions, 1980, 1983/180; 0.4 c.f. (1 archives box)
  Alphabetical index to the 1980 constituent correspondence.
- Part 7 (1984/026): Additions, 1979-1982, 1984/026; 19.4 c.f. (19 record center cartons and 1 archives box)
  Constituent correspondence to and from Governor Lee Sherman Dreyfus, 1979-1982. A portion of the accession is arranged numerically by code, there is an index in box 20. There is also correspondence arranged alphabetically, and state and federal agency correspondence. Included are incoming letters, copies of replies, and inter-office memoranda concerning the inquiry.
  - Constituent correspondence, numerical by code, 1979-1982
    - 5-1000 (Box 1)
    - 1001-1675 (Box 2)
    - 1676-2275 (Box 3)
    - 2276-2875 (Box 4)
    - 2876-3499 (Box 5)
    - 3501-4175 (Box 6)
    - 4176-4775 (Box 7)
    - 4776-5225 (Box 8)
    - 5226-5700 (Box 9)
    - 5701-6150 (Box 10)
    - 6151-6675 (Box 11)
    - 6676-7300 (Box 12)
    - 7301-7850 (Box 13)
    - 7851-8400 (Box 14)
    - 8401-9072 (Box 15)
  - Alphabetical correspondence, 1979-1981
    - National Governors Association (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Dept. of Natural Resources (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Nunnery, Willie J., Deputy Secretary. Dept. of Administration, Wisconsin's Energy Outlook (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Dreyfus, Lee Sherman, Governor, Open Primary Task Force (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Pabst, Richard, defendant, case number 2-255139, Circuit Court, Milwaukee, State of Wisconsin, partial transcript (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Jackson, Lowell, Secretary, Dept. of Transportation, parking Citation inquiry (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - People for Dreyfus political action committee (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Photographs, ordering information (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Dreyfus pins, campaign (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Executive Office, Division of State Planning and Energy (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - John Paul II, Pope, telegram of condolence, 1981 May 13 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Prairie du Chien bridge (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Prayer breakfast (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Presidential candidates, congratulations and replies, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Presidential election, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Prison siting (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Public defender (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Public Instruction, Dept. of (DPI) (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Public Service Commission (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Reagan, Ronald, presidential candidate, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Red Carpet Club, United Airlines (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Refugee family, (Bunna family of Thailand) (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Regulation and Licensing, Boards (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Republican Party
      - Wisconsin (Box 16, Folder 24)
      - National Convention, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 25)
      - Wisconsin, Eighth District caucus, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 26)
      - Wisconsin, state convention, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 27)
      - Invoices (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Republican Governors Association (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Revenue, Dept. of (DOR) (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Sales tax proposal, letter to local governments (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Schlitz, Strohs and Heileman (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Phillips, Vel, Secretary of State of Wisconsin (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Security, elected officials (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - U.S. Senate candidates (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - Small business
      - Small Business Administration (Box 16, Folder 36)
      - Governor's Conference on Small Business (Box 16, Folder 37)
      - Minority business operations (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - Snow (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - Soo Locks closing (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - State Capitol and Executive Residence Board (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - State Patrol, Wisconsin (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - State of the State North 1979 (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - Stevens Point Action Committee (Box 16, Folder 44)
    - Tax plan, 1981-1983 (Box 16, Folder 45)
    - Telecommunications (Box 16, Folder 46)
    - Telephone, Remote Service Access User (Box 16, Folder 47)
    - Trade Mission, Wisconsin (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Transportation, Dept. of (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Turnaround Through Partnership, Upper Great Lakes Regional Commission (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Veteran Affairs, Board of (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Veterinary medicine (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Washington, D.C. office, Local Affairs and Development, Dept. of (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Watchmaking Examining Board (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Weimar Republic (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Williams, Mary, memo file (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Wisconsin State Employees Union (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Women, status of (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Word processing (employment vacancy) (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - York, Stan, Assistant to the Governor (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Youth Awards, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 14-16)
  - State and federal agency correspondence, 1979-1980
    - Administration, Dept. of (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Agriculture, Dept. of (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Anderson, Greg, memoranda (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Appointments (for executive officer positions) (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Arts Board, Wisconsin (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Association for Public Broadcasting (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Attorney General of Wisconsin (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Authorizations for security protection (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Basic skills (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Bee Poop remark of Governor Dreyfus, responses (Box 17, Folder 26-27)
    - Blue Book, Wisconsin (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Budget, Wisconsin State, 4.4% cut (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Building Commission, Wisconsin (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Caterpillar Tractor Company, Peoria, Illinois (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Child, International Year of (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Christmas card (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - Columbian Art Works Inc. (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - Constituent relations (Box 17, Folder 35)
    - Constitutional Amendment to limit a Constitutional Convention (Box 17, Folder 36)
    - Conferences (Box 17, Folder 37)
    - Candidates, U.S. Congress (Box 17, Folder 38)
    - Constituent correspondence, miscellaneous (Box 17, Folder 39)
    - Criminal Justice, Wisconsin Council on (Box 17, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence, miscellaneous (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - County government, organization and administration (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Cuban refugees, final report (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Defense proposal (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Deininger, Kris, personal secretary to the Governor (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Defense, Dept. of (federal agency) (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Development, Dept. of (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Disaster Preparedness, Conference on (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Dreyfus profile (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Dreyfus memoranda (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Education Commission of the States (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Elections Board (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Electrical generation options (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Emergency powers (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Emergency Government, Division of (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Employment Relations, Dept. of (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Employment Relations, Joint Committee on (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - State Employment Report (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Energy Policy Task Force (Box 18, Folder 20-21)
    - American Energy Week, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 22-23)
    - Ethics statement (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Executive Office (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Executive Residence (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Export-Import Bank (federal agency) (Box 81, Folder 27)
    - Federal, Executive Office of the President of the United States (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Federalism (i.e. federal government objectives) (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Federal Emergency Management Agency, FEMA (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Energy, Dept. of (federal agency) (Box 18, Folder 31)
      - Fuel conservation (Box 18, Folder 32)
      - Fuel, Economic Regulatory Administration (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Gifts (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Goals and objectives (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Goethe (eagle flies alone quotation) (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Grass roots poll (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - Gundersen, Steve, Third Congressional District candidate, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - Haas, Mike notes (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - Hawaii (Box 18, Folder 40)
    - Health and Social Services, miscellaneous (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - Hessen (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Historical Society of Wisconsin (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Housing and Urban Development (federal agency) (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Inaugural, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Industry, Labor and Human Relations, Dept. of, Noll, Joe, resignation and miscellaneous (Box 19, Folder 4-5)
    - Issues (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Kaestner, Sue Ann, White House Fellowship application, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Kraus, Bill (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - La Fleur, Joe (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Law Enforcement Response Group (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Legislature (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Lewis, Margaret (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Li, Wan, Vice Premier, People's Republic of China (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Lincoln, Abraham, article (Dreyfus agriculture speech, 1980) (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Lindner, Ken (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Local Affairs and Development, Dept. of (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Mail control correspondence (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Merger (Dept. of Transportation and City of Waukesha) (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Midwestern Governors' Conference, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Military affairs (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Milwaukee police (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Milwaukee/Southeastern Wisconsin (Executive) Office proposal (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Milwaukee Road (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Minority initiatives (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous for Records Center (Box 19, Folder 25-26)
    - Moyers, Bill (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Murphy, Todd (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 19, Folder 29-31)
    - Local officials' mail (Box 19, Folder 32-33)
  - Correspondence index
    - 1979, name and subject (Box 20)
    - 1980, name and subject (Box 20)
    - 1981, name and subject (Box 20)
    - 1982, name (Box 20)
    - 1982, subject (Box 20)
- Part 8 (1985/172): Additions, 1979, 1982, 1985/172; 29.6 c.f. (29 record center cartons and 2 archives boxes)
  Constituent correspondence to Governor Dreyfus for 1979 and 1982. Files are arranged numerically by code. Included are incoming letters, copies of replies, inter-office memoranda concerning the inquiry, and face sheets showing office routing and other administrative information.
  - Constituent correspondence - numerical by code
    - 1979
      - 0-699 (Box 1)
      - 700-2499 (Box 2)
      - 2500-3499 (Box 3)
      - 3500-3684 (Box 4)
      - 3685-3999 (Box 5)
      - 4000-4999 (Box 6)
      - 5000-5999 (Box 7)
      - 6000-6899 (Box 8)
      - 6900-7449 (Box 9)
      - 7450-7999 (Box 10)
      - 8000-8699 (Box 11)
      - 8700-9599 (Box 12)
      - 9600-10499 (Box 13)
      - 10500-11699 (Box 14)
      - 11700-12699 (Box 15)
      - 12700-13599 (Box 16)
      - 13600-14499 (Box 17)
    - 1982
      - 62000-63899 (Box 18)
      - 63900-64499 (Box 19)
      - 64500-65299 (Box 20)
      - 65300-66199 (Box 21)
      - 66200-67299 (Box 22)
      - 67300-68299 (Box 23)
      - 68300-69199 (Box 24)
      - 69200-70199 (Box 25)
      - 70200-71099 (Box 26)
      - 71100-72899 (Box 27)
      - 72900-73599 (Box 28)
      - 73600-73799 (Box 29)
      - 73800-73999 (Box 30)
      - 74000-74799 (Box 31)
      - Constituent mail uncoded (Box 32)
- Part 9 (1986/070): Additions, 1978-1980, 1986/070; 16.0 c.f. (16 record center cartons)
  Constituent correspondence to Governor Dreyfus for 1978-1980. Files are arranged numerically by code. Included are incoming letters, copies of replies, inter-office memoranda concerning the inquiry, and face sheets showing office routing and other administrative information. There is also a small amount of legal policy correspondence.
  - Constituent correspondence - numerical by code 1978-1980
    - 1978
      - 21,000-21,999 (Box 1)
    - 1979
      - 22,000-22,499 (Box 2)
    - 1979-1980
      - 22,500-22,999 (Box 3)
    - 1979
      - 23,000-23,599 (Box 4)
      - 23,600-23,999 (Box 5)
      - 24,000-24,799 (Box 6)
      - 24,800-24,999 (Box 7)
      - 25,000-25,599 (Box 8)
      - 25,600-25,999 (Box 9)
      - 26,000-26,599 (Box 10)
      - 26,600-26,999 (Box 11)
      - 14,000-15,699 (Box 12)
      - 16,800-17,599 (Box 13)
      - 17,600-18,499 (Box 14)
      - Legal policy correspondence (Box 15)
      - 15,700-16,799 (Box 16)
- Part 10 (1986/197): Additions, 1978, 1986/197; 0.4 c.f. (1 archives box)
  Constituent correspondence to Governor Dreyfus during the 1978 campaign regarding debates and his position on various issues.
- Part 11 (1987/155): Additions, 1979-1980, 1987/155; 9.0 c.f. (9 record center cartons)
  Constituent correspondence addressed to Governor Lee Sherman Dreyfus, 1979-1980, arranged by numerical code. Included are incoming letters, copies of replies, inter-office memoranda concerning the inquiry, and face sheets showing office routing and other administrative information.
  - Constituent correspondence
    - 1979-1980
      - 18,500-19,449 (Box 5)
      - 19,450-20,249 (Box 6)
      - 20,250-21,199 (Box 7)
      - 21,200-21,849 (Box 8)
      - 27,000-27,699 (Box 12)
    - 1980
      - 27,700-28,599 (Box 13)
      - 28,600-29,299 (Box 14)
      - 29,300-29,999 (Box 15)
      - 30,000-30,999 (Box 16)